WILLIAM BRENDEL

He / Him / His

STRATEGIST • INNOVATOR • PIONEER

brendel.william@gmail.com
+1 (415) 539-5322
linkedin.com/in/william-brendel

SUMMARY

Snap Inc. amazon Google Software Engineering: 20+ years

2x Founder Machine Learning (ML): 18+ years

30+ patents and publications in Al Tech Industry: 13+ years

with 1800+ citations

Management and product strategy: 8+ years

TOGETHER, WE SUCCEED

Ready to scale your business, grow your team, or harness new tech in a fast-paced world? It's easy to feel stuck on how to execute. As a 2x founder, I have been in your shoes. With over a decade of experience at tech giants, I've launched products used by 100M+ daily users. No secret here: success is about execution and discipline. It's prioritizing MVPs, being agile, embracing failure while iterating quickly. It's about putting both business and users first. It's not just thinking outside the box, it's leading by example. That's how, together, we succeed.

EDUCATION

▶ PhD in Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence, Oregon State University, Corvallis, OR
June 2011

Master in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, CPE Lyon, France

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Inovexus

Mentor / Advisor
July 2023 - Present

Giving back to entrepreneurs by sharing my experience both as a Technical and Product Executive:

- Currently mentoring 2 startups, invyo.io and quideos.com
- \$2M seed funding raised after 9 months in the mentorship program

Crossroads Venture Studio, Inc.

Founder / General Partner

May 2023 - Present

Provide the initial team, strategic direction to reach product-market fit, and execution to startup launch:

- 8+ projects, including gococo.ai and automarketer.ai see our portfolio: crossroadsventurestudio.com
- 62.5% success rate (seed funding and/or bootstrapping to first customer)

Heali Al

Co-Founder / Chief Science Officer / Head of Product

May 2019 - May 2023

Co-founded a health-tech startup to help people with chronic disease to reduce their symptoms via personalized nutrition:

- Recruited and directed a team of 2-12 engineers, product designers, and UX researchers
- Architected and implemented Al-based nutrition technologies, supporting 200+ medical conditions
- \$4M fundraised, 8 digits business valuation

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Snap Inc.

Technical Program Manager / Senior Research Scientist

May 2016 - May 2019

Supported Snap's research team's growth and monitored 40+ projects impacting 188M+ DAU:

- 10+ research domains, including face analysis, NLP, scene understanding, augmented reality, video analysis
- Published: privacy-preserving friend recommendation 14% revival of dead users, 7% user engagement
- Designed: Bitmoji recommendation in the chat interface 8% increase in user engagement

Amazon • A9

Machine Learning Researcher / Technical Product Manager

November 2012 - May 2016

Defined, developed, and shipped products for A9's visual search team, servicing 200M+ DAU:

- Spearheaded our mobile brand logo detection and recognition project real-time performance at 100fps
- Blueprinted the visual search database, the annotation and evaluation platform 12M+ images and labels

Google • Youtube

Machine Learning Engineer

August 2011 - November 2012

Initiated and supervised the Suggested Edits project – an automatic system for poor-quality video detection and correction:

- Engineered and scaled the feature to the entire YouTube video corpus, impacting 94M+ DAU
- Created 10+ various video effects and filters

SCIENTIFIC COMMUNITY SERVICE

IEEE/CVF Computer Society Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition

➡ Publication Chair May 2017 - May 2019

Coordinated the publication process for 2 editions, with 2000+ papers issued for each edition.

IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision

Publication Chair
May 2018 − May 2019

Organized the publication process for WACV18, with 200+ papers released for the year.

SKILLS, QUALITIES, VALUES AND PERSONALITY



